<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Assignment Tab on Fugalist</title>
    <link>//fugalist.web.app/docs/tool/assignment-tab/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Assignment Tab on Fugalist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="//fugalist.web.app/docs/tool/assignment-tab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//fugalist.web.app/docs/tool/assignment-tab/header/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fugalist.web.app/docs/tool/assignment-tab/header/</guid>
      <description>The Assignment Table Header #  The assignment-table header shows all the playing techniques that the expression map supports and how they are grouped.
Each column is called an axis.
 The first axis (Length) consists of the Dorico playing techniques that indicate note duration: Normal, Staccato, Staccatissimo, Tenuto, and Staccato-tenuto. The second axis (Legato) consists of Normal and Legato. The third axis (Vibrato) consists of Normal and Non vibrato. The fourth axis (Attack) consists of Normal and Marcato.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Body</title>
      <link>//fugalist.web.app/docs/tool/assignment-tab/body/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fugalist.web.app/docs/tool/assignment-tab/body/</guid>
      <description>Assignment Tab Body #  The body of the tab is just a bunch of rows, one for each combination of the playing techniques. If you add or delete playing techniques, or rearrange the grouping, the rows of the table body will change to reflect that.
Here is one row:
The first five columns represent a particular combination of playing techniques. This example row will apply to any note where the active playing techniques are exactly non vibrato and marcato.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing-technique filters</title>
      <link>//fugalist.web.app/docs/tool/assignment-tab/filters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fugalist.web.app/docs/tool/assignment-tab/filters/</guid>
      <description>Playing Technique Filters #  The column header of the Length axis looks like this:
We saw earlier that clicking on the button labeled Length opens the axis-editor dialog. Clicking on a playing technique such as staccato toggles the visibility of table rows containing that technique. I.e., if you toggle Staccato off, all the rows containing Staccato will be hidden. If you toggle it on, they become visible again.
You can toggle each playing technique individually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bulk Assignment</title>
      <link>//fugalist.web.app/docs/tool/assignment-tab/bulk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fugalist.web.app/docs/tool/assignment-tab/bulk/</guid>
      <description>Bulk Assignment #  Frequently, after narrowing visible rows down, you want to apply the same sound to all the visible rows. To continue the example from the previous section, you might want to assign &amp;ldquo;harsh staccato&amp;rdquo; to all the rows that have marcato in addition to either staccato or staccatissimo. Bulk sound assignment lets you do that.
The rightmost header in the assignment tab looks like this:
The top dropdown (initially blank) lets you pick any VST or Composite sound that you&amp;rsquo;ve defined.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
