<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fugalist</title>
    <link>//fugalist-docs.web.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Fugalist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="//fugalist-docs.web.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//fugalist-docs.web.app/docs/tool/assignment-tab/header/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fugalist-docs.web.app/docs/tool/assignment-tab/header/</guid>
      <description>The Assignment Table Header #  The assignment-table header shows all the playing techniques that the expression map supports and how they are grouped.
Fugalist starts you off with a small selection of playing techniques applicable to almost any instrument:
Each column&amp;mdash;Length, Legato, etc.&amp;mdash;is called an axis. Fugalist will create a Dorico mutual-exclusion group for each axis (unless it contains only a single playing technique).  You can use the Axis Editor to add and delete playing techniques or to add and delete entire axes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//fugalist-docs.web.app/docs/tool/assignment-tab/axis-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fugalist-docs.web.app/docs/tool/assignment-tab/axis-editor/</guid>
      <description>Axis Editor #  Clicking on the name of the column opens a dialog that lets you edit that group of playing techniques:
Here you can
 change the name of the axis add or delete playing techniques from the axis move the axis left or right if that makes more sense to you add a new axis delete an axis.  Fugalist provides a default set of axes to get started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//fugalist-docs.web.app/docs/tool/overview-tab/fields/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fugalist-docs.web.app/docs/tool/overview-tab/fields/</guid>
      <description>Overview Fields #  Project ID #  A unique identifier for this project.
Created #  The time the project was created.
Current version #  Fugalist automatically updates the version when you share your expression map.
If you have never shared, the &amp;ldquo;current&amp;rdquo; version will be 1.
When (if) you share the first time, version 1 is shared, and the &amp;ldquo;current&amp;rdquo; version is immediately incremented to 2. Further modification will go into version 2, which is not yet shared.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Base Sounds</title>
      <link>//fugalist-docs.web.app/docs/tool/vst-tab/base/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fugalist-docs.web.app/docs/tool/vst-tab/base/</guid>
      <description>Base Sounds #  This is where you enter the sounds you want to use from your VST instrument. To add a new sound, click the + sign and fill in the blanks. Here&amp;rsquo;s one example row:
Name #  Give the sound a name that you&amp;rsquo;ll recognize later. It will show up on the Assignment tab.
Start #  Add the MIDI events to send to start the sound, separated by commas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Body</title>
      <link>//fugalist-docs.web.app/docs/tool/assignment-tab/body/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fugalist-docs.web.app/docs/tool/assignment-tab/body/</guid>
      <description>Assignment Tab Body #  The body of the tab is just a bunch of rows, one for each combination of the playing techniques. If you add or delete playing techniques, or rearrange the grouping, the rows of the table body will change to reflect that.
Here is one row:
The first five columns represent a particular combination of playing techniques. It will apply to any note where the active playing techniques are exactly non vibrato and marcato.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//fugalist-docs.web.app/docs/tool/add-ons/add-ons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fugalist-docs.web.app/docs/tool/add-ons/add-ons/</guid>
      <description>Add-on Techniques #  Sometimes the planets align: your VST instrument will have a control that is
 independent of all the others, and corresponds exactly to a Dorico playing technique.  If this happens, you&amp;rsquo;re in luck.
For example, you may find a VST instrument that uses CC3 to control attack. Low values mean gentle attack, high values mean marcato attack. Regardless of what else is going on, CC3 controls note attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//fugalist-docs.web.app/docs/tool/overview-tab/actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fugalist-docs.web.app/docs/tool/overview-tab/actions/</guid>
      <description>Action Buttons #  Download #  Clicking the download button first regenerates the expression map if changes have been made. Then it downloads the latest version of the generated Dorico expression map to your local machine.
Copy URL to clipboard #  This button copies the URL of the latest version of the generated Dorico expression map. The URL remains the same for each version of the expression map. The URL changes when the version changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing-technique filters</title>
      <link>//fugalist-docs.web.app/docs/tool/assignment-tab/filters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fugalist-docs.web.app/docs/tool/assignment-tab/filters/</guid>
      <description>Playing Technique Filters #  The column header of the Length axis looks like this:
We saw earlier that clicking on the Length button opens the axis-editor dialog. Clicking on a playing technique such as staccato toggles the visibility of table rows containing that technique. I.e., if you toggle Staccato off, all the rows containing Staccato will be hidden. If you toggle it on, they become visible again.
You can toggle each playing technique individually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIDI Event Syntax</title>
      <link>//fugalist-docs.web.app/docs/tool/vst-tab/midi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fugalist-docs.web.app/docs/tool/vst-tab/midi/</guid>
      <description>Specifying MIDI Events #  MIDI Key Switch #  A MIDI key switch can be specified either as a note number (0-127) or as a chromatic note plus an octave.
MIDI Note Number #  To specify a MIDI note number, just prefix the number with KS:
KS3 ks13 ks 7  The default velocity is 127. If you need to specify a different velocity, you can specify the velocity after an &amp;ldquo;=&amp;rdquo; sign.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bulk Assignment</title>
      <link>//fugalist-docs.web.app/docs/tool/assignment-tab/bulk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fugalist-docs.web.app/docs/tool/assignment-tab/bulk/</guid>
      <description>Bulk Assignment #  Frequently, after focusing in on some rows, you want to apply the same sound to all the visible rows. To continue the example from the previous section, you might want to assign &amp;ldquo;harsh staccato&amp;rdquo; to all the rows that have marcato in addition to either staccato or staccatissimo. Bulk sound assignment lets you do that.
The rightmost header in the assignment tab looks like this:
The top dropdown (initially blank) lets you pick any VST or Composite sound that you&amp;rsquo;ve defined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//fugalist-docs.web.app/docs/introduction/notation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fugalist-docs.web.app/docs/introduction/notation/</guid>
      <description>Music Notation #  Western music notation starts with staffs, clefs, and notes. Then it gets complicated. For hundreds of years, people have been adding new symbols and annotations to music notation to better express how the music is intended to sound.
Dorico supports pretty much any notation you can imagine. Hundreds of notations are built in, and you can create your own if you need to. During playback, Dorico does an amazing job of keeping track of all the notations that apply to a particular note.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//fugalist-docs.web.app/docs/tool/composite-tab/fields/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fugalist-docs.web.app/docs/tool/composite-tab/fields/</guid>
      <description>Fields #  Name #  Give your composite sound a name.
Condition #  The condition determines which branch of the composite sound to use for a particular note. In the example above, the first branch is used if the note length (as computed by Dorico) is less than short. The second branch is used otherwise. That means that short notes will use your staccato patch, and longer notes use the sustain patch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//fugalist-docs.web.app/docs/tool/composite-tab/condition-syntax/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fugalist-docs.web.app/docs/tool/composite-tab/condition-syntax/</guid>
      <description>Condition Syntax #  Fugalist is pretty flexible about how to write conditions. You can use comparison operators to combine the actual note length (NoteLength) and Dorico&amp;rsquo;s predefined note lengths.
Examples of simple comparisons:
NoteLength == veryShort note length &amp;lt; medium very short &amp;lt; note length note length == very long  Dorico&amp;rsquo;s predefined note lengths:
 very short: shorter than 0.1875 seconds, (i.e., shorter than a dotted 16th note at 120bpm) short: between 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Dorico Uses an Expression Map</title>
      <link>//fugalist-docs.web.app/docs/introduction/how-its-used/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fugalist-docs.web.app/docs/introduction/how-its-used/</guid>
      <description>How does Dorico use an expression map? #  For each note in a score, Dorico computes the pitch, duration, volume, and the set of playing techniques that are active.
Dorico itself takes care of pitch and duration for the most part, so you usually don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry too much about them.
However, you can adjust Dorico&amp;rsquo;s durations if you need to.  Dorico needs a little help with the volume.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tiny Example</title>
      <link>//fugalist-docs.web.app/docs/introduction/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fugalist-docs.web.app/docs/introduction/example/</guid>
      <description>Tiny Example #  To be concrete, suppose we want to support the following playing techniques:
 Normal and tenuto lengths Normal and legato note connections Normal and pizzicato technique  Here&amp;rsquo;s a complete table of sensible combinations, eight in all:
   Length Legato Technique on off vol etc     Normal Normal Normal       Normal Normal Pizz       Normal Legato Normal       Normal Legato Pizz       Tenuto Normal Normal       Tenuto Normal Pizz       Tenuto Legato Normal       Tenuto Legato Pizz        What remains is to fill in the blanks: specify on events, off events, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So What&#39;s the Problem?</title>
      <link>//fugalist-docs.web.app/docs/introduction/problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fugalist-docs.web.app/docs/introduction/problem/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s the problem? #  This all seems pretty straightforward: figure out which playing techniques to support. Then create a table with one row for each combination of playing techniques. Assign on events, off events, etc., for each row.
The problem is scale. Suppose you want to support
 five note articulations (normal, staccato, staccatissimo, tenuto, and staccato-tenuto), normal and legato note transitions normal and marcato attack, normal and non-vibrato, and normal, pizzicato, sul tasto, and sul pont.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
