<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VST Sounds Tab on Fugalist</title>
    <link>//fugalist.web.app/docs/tool/vst-tab/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VST Sounds Tab on Fugalist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="//fugalist.web.app/docs/tool/vst-tab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Base Sounds</title>
      <link>//fugalist.web.app/docs/tool/vst-tab/base/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fugalist.web.app/docs/tool/vst-tab/base/</guid>
      <description>Base Sounds #  This is where you enter the sounds you want to use from your VST instrument. To add a new sound, click the + sign and fill in the blanks:
Name #  Give the sound a name that you&amp;rsquo;ll recognize later. It will show up on the Assignment tab.
Start #  Add the MIDI events to send to start the sound, separated by commas. See Specifying MIDI events for details of how to write MIDI events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//fugalist.web.app/docs/tool/vst-tab/add-ons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fugalist.web.app/docs/tool/vst-tab/add-ons/</guid>
      <description>Add-on Techniques #  Sometimes the planets align: your VST instrument will have a control that is
 independent of all the others, and corresponds exactly to a Dorico playing technique.  If this happens, you&amp;rsquo;re in luck.
Example, you may find a VST instrument that uses CC3 to control attack. Low values mean gentle attack, high values mean marcato attack. Regardless of what else is going on, CC3 controls note attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIDI Event Syntax</title>
      <link>//fugalist.web.app/docs/tool/vst-tab/midi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fugalist.web.app/docs/tool/vst-tab/midi/</guid>
      <description>Specifying MIDI Events #  MIDI Key Switch #  A MIDI key switch can be specified either as a note number (0-127) or a chromatic note plus an octave.
MIDI Note Number #  To specify a MIDI note number, just prefix the number with KS:
KS3 ks13 ks 7  The default velocity is 127. If you need to specify a different velocity, you can specify the velocity after an &amp;ldquo;=&amp;rdquo; sign.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
